<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<dmodule xmlns:dc="http://www.purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.s1000d.org/S1000D_4-0-1/xml_schema_flat/learning.xsd">
  <rdf:Description>
    <dc:creator>06RT9</dc:creator>
    <dc:title>Bicycle - Planning information: Intervention definition</dc:title>
    <dc:subject>Bicycle - Planning information: Intervention definition</dc:subject>
    <dc:publisher>06RT9</dc:publisher>
    <dc:contributor>06RT9</dc:contributor>
    <dc:date>2009-08-22</dc:date>
    <dc:type>text</dc:type>
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:identifier>S1000DBIKE-AAA-D00-00-00-00AA-932A-A-H30A_001-00</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>01_cc51</dc:rights>
  </rdf:Description>
  <identAndStatusSection>
    <dmAddress>
      <dmIdent>
        <dmCode modelIdentCode="S1000DBIKE" systemDiffCode="AAA" systemCode="D00" subSystemCode="0" subSubSystemCode="0" assyCode="00" disassyCode="00" disassyCodeVariant="AA" infoCode="932" infoCodeVariant="A" itemLocationCode="A" learnCode="H30" learnEventCode="A" />
        <language countryIsoCode="US" languageIsoCode="en" />
        <issueInfo issueNumber="001" inWork="00" />
      </dmIdent>
      <dmAddressItems>
        <issueDate year="2009" month="07" day="22" />
        <dmTitle>
          <techName>Bicycle</techName>
          <infoName>Planning information: Intervention definition</infoName>
        </dmTitle>
      </dmAddressItems>
    </dmAddress>
    <dmStatus>
      <security securityClassification="01"></security>
      <responsiblePartnerCompany enterpriseCode="06RT9"></responsiblePartnerCompany>
      <originator></originator>
      <applic>
        <displayText></displayText>
      </applic>
      <brexDmRef>
        <dmRef>
          <dmRefIdent>
            <dmCode modelIdentCode="S1000D" systemDiffCode="A" systemCode="04" subSystemCode="1" subSubSystemCode="0" assyCode="0301" disassyCode="00" disassyCodeVariant="A" infoCode="022" infoCodeVariant="A" itemLocationCode="D" />
            <issueInfo issueNumber="005" inWork="00" />
            <language languageIsoCode="en" countryIsoCode="US" />
          </dmRefIdent>
        </dmRef>
      </brexDmRef>
      <qualityAssurance>
        <unverified></unverified>
      </qualityAssurance>
      <systemBreakdownCode>D0000</systemBreakdownCode>
    </dmStatus>
  </identAndStatusSection>
  <content>
    <learning>
      <learningPlan>
        <lcProject>
          <title>Project Title - SCORM 2004 Learning Content Package in S1000D: The Bike Example</title>
          <description>
            <para>This learning is sponsored by the National Bike Courier association. </para>
          </description>
          <lcClient>
            <title>Client: National Bike Courier Association (NBCA)</title>
            <description>
              <para>The NBCA's mission statement is to promote unity and solidarity within the messenger community and to raise the status of our profession.</para>
            </description>
          </lcClient>
          <lcPlanTitle>
            <title>Learning Plan Title: Getting to Know Your Bike</title>
            <description>
              <para>This lesson plan describes the learning needs and instructional strategies for teaching the parts of a bike and bike maintenance. </para>
            </description>
          </lcPlanTitle>
          <lcCIN>
            <title>Course Identification Number:</title>
            <description>
              <para>N00174-05-D-0003</para>
            </description>
          </lcCIN>
          <lcDelivDate>
            <title>Delivery Date:</title>
            <description>
              <para>20091228</para>
            </description>
          </lcDelivDate>
          <lcPlanSubject>
            <title>Learning Plan Subject Matter:</title>
            <description>
              <para>Bike description and general maintenance</para>
            </description>
          </lcPlanSubject>
          <lcPlanDescript>
            <title>Learning Plan Description: </title>
            <description>
              <para>The goal of the S1000D Bike Example is show and help the public understand how learning modules work and how they are compiled into SCORM 2004.</para>
            </description>
          </lcPlanDescript>
          <lcPlanPrereqs>
            <title>Learning Plan Prequisites:</title>
            <description>
              <para>There are no prerquisites for this Learning Plan.</para>
            </description>
          </lcPlanPrereqs>
        </lcProject>
        <lcIntervention>
          <title>Instructional Interventions</title>
          <shortDescr>Instructional measures designed to ease or resolve job performance problems in the workplace. </shortDescr>
          <lcInterventionItem>
            <title>Intervention Items</title>
            <shortDescr>
							Interventions that will be used in this course include: stimulate learner interest by gaining attention and building on prior knowledge; inform the learner of expections via learning objectives; provide material chunked into manageable pieces; sequence material appropriately for the learner; create interactive media and exercises to maintain interest; create interactive exercises (Knowledge Checks) to reinforce content; provide feedback.
						</shortDescr>
            <lcLearnStrat>
              <description>
                <para>
                  <emphasis>Learning Strategies:</emphasis>
                </para>
                <para>
									This course will consist of six modules - one introductory module and five content modules.
								</para>
                <para>
                  <randomList>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>Module 1 consists of one SCO. This SCO is designed to gain learner attention and provide the purpose for the course. No teaching points are presented; therefore, there is no learning objective for the SCO. This SCO will not be assessed.</para>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>Modules 2 - 6 each contain two SCOs. These SCOs present teaching points that support the module objectives. Each module has one terminal learning objective (TLO); and each SCO has one enabling objective (ELO). SCOs will contain instructional elements to keep the learner mentally and actively engaged. To reinforce the material, SCOs include content review questions. These ungraded questions will be imbedded throughout each SCO and may be in the form of multiple-choice single answer, multiple-choice multiple answer, ordering, matching, or hotspot image. Learners are given two attempts to achieve correct answers. Learners receive immediate feedback after each answer, correct or incorrect.</para>
                    </listItem>
                  </randomList>
                </para>
              </description>
            </lcLearnStrat>
            <lcPlanObjective>
              <description>
                <para>
                  <emphasis>Objectives:</emphasis>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <emphasis>Module 1 - Getting to Know Your Bike</emphasis>
                  <!-- More information to come-->
                </para>
                <para>
                  <emphasis>Module 2 - Bike Overview</emphasis>
                </para>
                <para>
									Terminal Objective - Given a bike, you will be able to name the main parts of a bike.
								</para>
                <para>
                  <randomList>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>
												SCO 1 - Bike Description
											</para>
                      <para>
												Enabling Objective - Given a photograph of a bike, you will be able to identify the main parts with 80 percent accuracy.
											</para>
                    </listItem>
                  </randomList>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <emphasis>Module 3 - Steering System</emphasis>
                </para>
                <para>
									Terminal Objective - Given a bike, you will be able to perform the steps to remove and install the parts of a bike's steering system.
								</para>
                <para>
                  <randomList>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>
												SCO 1 - Bike Description
											</para>
                      <para>
												Enabling Objective - Given a photograph of a bike, you will be able to identify the main parts with 80 percent accuracy.
											</para>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>
												SCO 2 - Steering System Installation and Removal
											</para>
                      <para>
												Enabling Objective - Given a bike, you will be able to describe how to install and remove a bike's steering system with 80 percent accuracy.
											</para>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>
												SCO 3 - Assessment
											</para>
                    </listItem>
                  </randomList>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <emphasis>Module 4 - Drive Train</emphasis>
                </para>
                <para>
									Terminal Objective - Given a bike, you will be able to perform the steps to maintain the drive train.
								</para>
                <para>
                  <randomList>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>SCO 1 - Parts of the Drive Train</para>
                      <para>Enabling Objective - Given a photograph of a bike, you will be able to identify the main parts with 80 percent accuracy.</para>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>SCO 2 - Drive Train Preventive Maintenance</para>
                      <para>Enabling Objective - Given a bike, you will be able to describe how to install and remove a bike's steering system with 80 percent accuracy.</para>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>
												SCO 3 - Assessment
											</para>
                    </listItem>
                  </randomList>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <emphasis>Module 5 - Wheels</emphasis>
                </para>
                <para>Terminal Objective - Given a bike, you will be able to perform the steps to maintain the wheels.</para>
                <para>
                  <randomList>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>SCO 1 - Parts of a Bike Wheel</para>
                      <para>Enabling Objective - Given photograph of a bike's wheels, you will be able to identify each part with 80 percent accuracy.</para>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>
												SCO 2 - Bike Wheel Maintenance
											</para>
                      <para>
												Enabling Objective - Given a bike, you will be able to describe how to maintain a bike's wheels with 80 percent accuracy.
											</para>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>SCO 3 - Assessment</para>
                    </listItem>
                  </randomList>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <emphasis>Module 6 - Brake System</emphasis>
                </para>
                <para>Terminal Objective - Given maintenance tools, you will be able to perform the steps to maintain the brake system.</para>
                <para>
                  <randomList>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>
												SCO 1 - Parts of the Brake System
											</para>
                      <para>
												Enabling Objective - Given photographs of a bike's brake system, you will be able to identify each part with 80 percent accuracy.
											</para>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>
												SCO 2 - Brake System Maintenance
											</para>
                      <para>
												Enabling Objective - Given maintenance procedures, you will be able to describe how to maintain a bike's brake system with 80 percent accuracy.
											</para>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>
												SCO 3 - Assessment
											</para>
                    </listItem>
                  </randomList>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <emphasis>Module 7 - Bike Operation</emphasis>
                </para>
                <para>Terminal Objective - Given a bike, you will be able to perform pre- and post operation procedures.</para>
                <para>
                  <randomList>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>
												SCO 1 - General Maintenance
											</para>
                      <para>
												Enabling Objective - Given general maintenance procedures, you will be able to describe how to maintain a bike for operation with 80% accuracy.
											</para>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>
												SCO 2 - Pre and Post Operation Procedures
											</para>
                      <para>
												Enabling Objective - Given pre and post operation procedures, you will be able to prepare a bike for operation.
											</para>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                      <para>
												SCO 3 - Assessment
											</para>
                    </listItem>
                  </randomList>
                </para>
              </description>
            </lcPlanObjective>
            <lcAssessment>
              <description>
                <para>
                  <emphasis>Assessment:</emphasis>
                </para>
                <para>Each content module will contain a post assessment. These assessments will contain questions that are directly related to the module's content SCOs. Questions will address each of the module's ELOs. Each test bank will be randomized and contain at least 3 questions per ELO. The passing score for the assessments is 80%. The number of attempts to pass the assessments will be unlimited.  </para>
              </description>
            </lcAssessment>
            <lcDelivery>
              <description>
                <para>
                  <emphasis>Delivery:</emphasis>
                </para>
                <para>The Getting to Know Your Bike course will meet SCORM 2004standards. It will reside on the SumTotal LMS located at the National Bike Courier Association (NBCA) headquarters in New York City. Learners will have access the course using a link from the SumTotal Virtual Campus.</para>
              </description>
            </lcDelivery>
          </lcInterventionItem>
        </lcIntervention>
        <lcTechnical />
      </learningPlan>
    </learning>
  </content>
</dmodule>